Brother.
哥
Dad.
爸
Xiang Yuansheng,
向远生
remember what you said
你那天在我家
at my house that day?
是怎么说的
You said you were done being a cop.
你说你不干警察了
Why did you
你为什么要
drag my daughter into this?
拉着我女儿在一起啊
You were acting together,
你们行动是在一起的呀
weren't you?
对吧
And there were so many of you.
而且还有那么多的人呢
But why?
不
Why was my daughter
咋偏偏我女儿
assaulted alone?
打成这个样子呢
Tell me why.
你告诉我为什么
Can you talk?
说话好吗
Say something!
说话呀
A bunch of useless people.
一群废物啊
Feng Sir.
冯科长
The station
分局接到
received a notification from the police hospital
警察医院的通知
about an injured officer.
有下属警员受伤
That's right.
是 是 是
I must come and check on the situation.
我只好来看一下情况
Yes, Sir.
是
She hasn't woken up yet.
她还没醒
Not awake?
没醒
Then go wake her up.
没醒就去把她叫醒啊
The doctor said her injuries are severe.
医生说她伤得很重
Does sympathy solve cases?
同情心能破案吗
Answering a few questions
回答几个问题
won't delay her recovery.
耽误不了她养伤
She hurt badly.
人都已经这样了
Can't you treat her as a human being?
你还把她当人吗
If too delicate, she shouldn't be a cop!
这么娇气就别当警察了
Thank you!
谢谢
You're right!
您说得太好了
Absolutely right!
太对了
Tianxiang,
天祥 走
get a stretcher
借个担架
and transfer her to civilian hospital.
转别的医院
Officer Luo,
骆警官
What do you want?
你想干什么
Let's talk this out.
有话好好说
Stay away from her.
离她远点儿
Are you out of your mind?
你疯了
Who do you think you are?
跟谁说话呢
I said, stay away from her.
我让你离她远点儿
Officer Xiang,
向警官
I'm convinced that
这么目中无人
you're really not suited
无视纪律
to be a policeman
我看你确实
with your disregard for others and disciplines.
不太适合当警察
My career
我的事儿
isn't up to you to decide.
你说了不算
Move!
躲开
Let me find you a car.
我帮您找辆车吧
The finest officers from the Fourth Station House
四所优秀的警员们
are all here, huh?
都在这儿了啊
Tell me,
说吧
who was involved
昨天晚上的事儿
in last night's incident?
都谁参与了
Feng Sir, they were all involved...
科长 他们几个都参与
Did I ask you?
我问你了吗
1556.
一五五六
A new officer?
新警员
What's your name?
叫什么名字
Tian Dongbao.
田冬宝
You speak.
你说
Last night...
昨天晚上
Last night, the station house responded
昨天晚上四所临时出警
to a burglary call.
处理一桩入室抢劫案
Probationary Officer Luo Minmin was assaulted.
实习警员骆珉敏被打伤
So Captain Chen
原来是陈队长
was responsible for the case.
负责的这个案子
Then tell me,
那你说说吧
who was it? Did you catch them?
什么人啊 抓到了吗
We didn't see the perpetrator.
没有看见作案人
Identity unknown.
不确定身份
Interesting.
有意思啊
You didn't see who did it.
你们没看见作案人员
So how did
那实习警员
the probationary officer get hurt?
是怎么受伤的
At that time...
当时
Shut up!
闭嘴
You speak.
你说
Last night, the Captain
昨天队长
had me searching for clues.
让我去搜查线索了
I wasn't at the scene.
我不在场
You.
你
We split up.
昨天我们分头行动的
I don't know how.
我不知道
You at the scene, Officer Xiang.
那只剩你了 向警官
Your turn.
你说说
I've resigned already.
我已经辞职了
You can't question me.
你问不着我
So none of you
所以你们是
knows anything?
没有一个人知道啊
You should know
那公安局的规定
the bureau's rules!
你们该知道吧
Probationary officers
实习警员
are not allowed to participate in dangerous activities!
不得参加危险活动
Captain Chen,
陈队长
I'd like to know how,
我倒想问问你
right after I warned you
你是怎么做到
yesterday afternoon,
昨天下午
you allowed a probationary officer
刚刚被我警告完之后
to break the rules
今天又让一名实习警员
and get seriously injured?
违规出警导致重伤的
It was my misjudgment.
是我判断失误
I thought
当时以为
it was a routine burglary,
是一个普通的入室盗窃
so I allowed her to respond.
所以才同意她出警
How did you receive the call?
怎么接的警
Someone called in.
有人打电话
Who answered?
谁接的警
I did.
我
Who made the call?
谁报的警
Not sure.
不清楚
Do you realize what you're saying?
你知道自己在说什么吗
Think twice before you speak.
你给老子想想清楚
All she said
当时只说了
was Wangyun Road No. 23.
望云路二十三号
The line had too much static.
电话杂音太大了
I could only tell it was a woman.
只能辨别是一名女性
When we got there
我们赶到
at Wangyun Apartments,
望云公寓的时候
we didn't see the caller.
没有见到报案人
Someone called the police
有人报了警
and hid herself from the police?
躲着不见警察
Maybe too scared
可能因为太害怕了
to show up.
不敢露面
So, the Fourth Station House,
所以你们四所
busy all night,
忙活了一整晚
full force deployed,
全员出警
and all you achieved besides
除了让一名实习警员
getting a probationary officer hurt
受伤以外
was nothing?
一无所获
Feng Sir,
科长
it's... it's all my fault.
都 都是我的错
After all, our station house
主 主要吧咱四所
hasn't handled such a big case before...
没经过这么大的案子
Incompetents! Are you senile?
废物 你老糊涂了
Don't move!
别动
Nobody move!
都别动
What are you doing?
干什么
Hands off!
住手
Take Chen away!
把陈浩给我拉出去
-Back off!
往后 往后
[If you can't manage your subordinates,]
要是管不好你的下属
[you better get out of here!]
你趁早给我滚蛋
[We will investigate this thoroughly,]
这不 追查追查
[to the bottom of it.]
一查到底 一查到底
As a Captain, your negligence
作为队长渎职
led to an officer badly injured.
导致下属警员受伤
I have no choice but to suspend you.
我现在不得不让你停职
Well done.
好样的
Captain.
队长
Let's go.
走吧
My face!
脸
You've all
我这张老脸
disgraced me!
让你们丢尽了
What a good girl she is!
好好的一个人
And now look at her!
现在成什么样了
Did any of you even think?
你们想过没有
She's not just an officer,
她不光是个警员
she's a young woman!
她还是个女孩子
Of course,
是
she's young, impulsive.
她年轻 她冲动
What about the rest of you?
你们呢
What about the older ones?
老的呢
[The one in this room!]
屋里的那个
[What are you all good for?]
你们都干什么吃的
I can't even be mad at you anymore!
我跟你们生不起这气
Might as well
要我看啊
take this opportunity
就趁这个机会
to disband the Fourth Station House.
四所解散吧
Better off disbanded.
解散了挺好的
Out of sight, out of mind.
我眼不见 心不烦
Everyone, dismiss.
散了吧 散了吧
All of you, get out!
滚 都滚
That's it.
行了
Go back now.
先回去吧
Dongbao,
冬宝
Go.
走
Hongfa, go back.
鸿发 回去了
Yuansheng,
向警官
that button
珉敏
Minmin was clutching yesterday...
昨天握在手里的扣子
She was so badly injured,
她都伤成那样了
yet she still
手里还紧紧
held onto that button.
握着这个扣子
I... I went through
我 我昨天我
every trash can
我把现场所有的垃圾桶
at the scene yesterday.
我都翻了个遍
I...
我
I couldn't find any clues.
我没有找到任何线索
Sorry.
对不起
I'm useless.
是我没用 是我没用
I'm so sorry, I'm useless!
对不起 是我没用
Hongfa,
鸿发
go and get some rest.
回去休息了
Now, Hongfa.
走了 鸿发
Since you joined the Station House,
自打你来了我们四所
we haven't had a single
我们一天安生日子
peaceful day!
没过过
Minmin got injured,
珉敏受伤
the inspector was slapped,
所长挨耳光
and now the Captain has been suspended.
现在队长也被停了职
All this trouble,
事情发展成这样
arise from the Mengs case.
全是因为孟家这案子
Xiang Yuansheng,
向远生
I don't even want to know
你到底是什么人
who you really are anymore.
我已经不想知道了
Since you've already handed in your resignation,
你既然已经交了辞呈
just leave us quickly.
就赶紧走吧
Only if you gone
只有你离开
can the Fourth Station House
我们四所
get back to how it used to be.
才能变成以前的样子
Don't take Erbai's words to heart.
二白说的话别往心里去
Your resignation is accepted.
你的辞呈我收了
Now go and check on Luo Minmin.
赶紧去看看骆珉敏
I'm sorry.
对不起啊
My police badge has been taken.
警员证已经收走了
My uniform and cap are here.
警服 警帽放在这儿
You'll be compensated
这个月的薪水
for this month.
会补给你的
Are your parents still in Fengxian District?
父母还在奉贤
Yes Sir.
在
They're doing alright?
挺好的吧他们
Quite alright.
挺好
Go visit them.
回去看看他们吧
As for what's next,
之后的路
just take it one step at a time.
走一步看一步吧
Say something.
说话呀
The job isn't done yet.
事情还没做完呢
Stubborn, you're so stubborn!
犟 你就犟
When you dig your heels in,
犟起来
not even eight horses can pull you back.
八匹马都拉不回来
Can you just listen to me for once?
你听我一句行不行
How old are you?
多大了
Almost thirty.
快三十的人了
Can't you just live
你就不能像
like a normal person?
正常人一样吗
Find a girlfriend,
找个女朋友
hold hands,
拉拉手
watch a movie.
看看电影
Wouldn't that be far better than
不比你现在这样子
what you're now?
强多了
Sounds good.
是挺好的
But my man almost died.
但我的人差点没了
I asked her
是我让她
to stay under that streetlamp.
留在路灯下面的
She was lying there, covered in blood.
她血淋淋躺在那儿
I wish it had been me.
我希望是我
Captain Chen,
陈队长
I've come to take back my resignation.
我来要回我的辞呈
Zhang Runjin?
张润金
In Shanghai?
跑到上海来了
You know him?
你认识他
Yes, I do.
认识
I once destroyed
我在广州
an Undercover Work Group of CPC
抓过一个共产党的
in Guangzhou,
地下小组
and he was their liaison man.
他是其中的交通员
He got away from me.
被他给跑了
I never thought he'd show up in Shanghai.
没想到跑到上海来了
Did he say anything before he passed out?
他昏迷前交代了什么
He said
他说
he went to Wangyun Apartments
他去望云路公寓
to meet a friend
找一个朋友
and got injured
遇到有匪徒抢劫
while helping chase a burglar.
帮忙的时候受了伤
He wouldn't say anything else.
其他的一概不说
But when I got him,
但是我抓到他的时候
he was making a phone call,
他正在打电话
looking very anxious.
神情很焦灼
I traced the location.
位置我查过了
It was from a public phone.
是个公用电话
We got this from the telephone company.
我们通过电话局查的
He made two calls.
他一共打了两遍
The first seemed to go unanswered,
第一遍可能是没人接
and he only started talking during the second one.
第二遍才看见他说话
But he was too far away
但是距离太远
to hear what he was saying.
听不见他说的是什么
If he was caught up
他出现在
near Meng Duoci,
那个孟多慈旁边
he's definitely a member
他就肯定是
of Deng Mingyuan's group.
邓铭远的组员
The person he was calling
那接电话的
must be his accomplice.
一定是他的同伙
It rang more than four times?
响了四声还没挂
That's not Mr. Zhang.
这不是老张
[Qiushi,]
秋实
[are you doing okay at Ms. Shi's place?]
你在石老师家还好吗
[I'm fine. How about Minmin?]
我还好 珉敏姐姐呢
[Did you find her?]
你们找到她了吗
We found her.
找到了
Is she alright?
她好不好
Is she hurt?
受伤了没有
[She just got home from the hospital.]
她刚刚从医院回家了
Qiushi,
秋实
I'm calling to
我打电话
ask you one thing.
是还有一件事儿要问你
[Who sent the cake]
桌上的蛋糕
[on the table?]
是谁送过来的
[Uncle Luo delivered it in person.]
蛋糕是骆伯伯送来的
Did Officer Luo's father
骆警官的父亲
visited you?
他来过家里
Did he tell you
他有说是怎么知道
how he knew this address?
这个地址的吗
No.
没有
[I got it.]
我知道了
Take care of yourself.
照顾好自己
Mr. Luo,
骆先生
sorry to bother you.
打扰了
I must confirm something
有些事情
with you.
我必须跟您确认
You are not a police officer.
你有资格吗
Officer Xiang,
向警官
what happened to you?
怎么弄成这样
Have some warm water.
快喝口热水
Wipe it yourself.
快擦擦
Who let him in?
谁把他放进来的
I heard someone was knocking on the door.
我听见有人一直在敲门
Dad, Xiang is a good person.
爸 向警官又不是坏人
Check the decoction.
你去看着药
What do you want?
你想干什么
on the day Officer Luo was assaulted,
骆警官受伤那天
you visited the apartment
您去公寓
and brought a cake to Qiushi.
给秋实送过蛋糕
I need to know
我想知道
how you knew
您是怎么知道
that address?
那个地址的
Had you ever told the address
您有把那个地址
to anyone else?
告诉过其他人吗
What do you mean?
你什么意思啊
You are suspecting one of us
你是怀疑
had collided the suspect.
我们家里的人串通犯人
Told him the address
把地址告诉他
And asked him to hurt my daughter?
把我女儿打成这样
Are you out of your mind?
你动动脑子好不啦
Sister.
姐
It's me.
没事儿 没事儿
My hand slipped.
是我不小心打翻了
I'll clean it now.
我马上打扫
Be careful.
毛手毛脚的呢
I'll fetch the broom.
我去拿扫把
You get out of my house.
你赶紧滚
Qinqin, stay where you are.
勤芹 你别过来
Don't get hurt.
别扎着你
Mr. Luo.
骆先生
Thank you for
谢谢你那天
arranging a rickshaw
叫了辆黄包车
to send us back home.
送我和秋实回家
I have some questions
我有一些问题
to ask that driver of the rickshaw.
想要问一下那位车夫
Could you please
能麻烦你
take me there?
带我过去一趟吗
I'm busy today.
今天不太方便
I'll clean it
我把这儿收拾了
and cook a diner for Minmin later.
晚点我得给珉敏去做饭
I'm sorry.
不好意思啊
Officer Xiang.
向警官
Did my brother make any trouble?
我哥哥是惹麻烦了吗
No, it's just a casual talk.
没有 我就随便问问
Could you please
那你待会儿进去
don't mention what had happened
见我姐姐的时候
on that day
千万别和她提
to my sister?
那天的事儿
She finally woke up
她今天早上
this morning.
才好不容易醒过来
She was freaked out that day.
她那天真的吓坏了
Well.
我
I'd better not bother her.
我就不进去了吧
You're here to visit her today,
你今天不就是来
aren't you?
看我姐姐的吗
The Fourth Station House is investigating
四所在调查
the case she got involved in.
骆警官受伤的案子
And I'm here to make inquiries.
我是来搜集线索的
Sorry to bother.
不好意思 打扰了
Officer Xiang,
向警官
I had a button
我手里
in my hand.
有一颗扣子
Did anyone see it?
有人看见了吗
It's with me.
扣子在我手里
I tore the button out
那颗扣子
from the clothes
是我从凶手身上
of the suspect.
拽下来的
Will it be a clue?
不知道是不是线索
I heard that you're investigating.
你要去查吗
Will it help you?
它有没有用
Don't worry.
放心
It's an important clue.
扣子有用
It'll lead us to the criminal.
一定会有用的
Liu.
老六
Have you seen
你看见
who put the eggs on my doorstep?
谁把鸡蛋放我门口的
No, I haven't.
刚忙着呢 没看见
Who put the eggs here?
谁把鸡蛋放这儿的
Whose eggs?
谁送的鸡蛋
Dad, it must be the policeman
爸 这一看就是
from the Fourth Station House.
四所的人送来
They sent the eggs to my sister.
看望姐姐的
I would rather some hens
我宁愿是
laid them by mistake.
鸡在我门口下的蛋
Don't touch it.
别动
Luo, if you don’t want them,
骆师傅 你这鸡蛋不要
I'll have them.
我可收着了
What are you doing?
干吗呢
Your dad agreed
你 你爸不是说了吗
to give it to me.
给我收着
You misjudged his courtesy.
我爹说给你就给你
They are gifts to us.
这别人送我们家的
Greedy.
什么便宜都要贪
What a family it is.
这一家都什么人
You stole the eggs?
鸡蛋是你偷的
I bought it.
我买的
I never steal things.
怎么会偷的呢
Why didn't you tell them?
那你躲什么呀
I don't know how to face her family.
不知道怎么面对她家人
How's Minmin.
珉敏怎么样
She's better.
好一些了
Good.
那就好
I wonder
有件事儿
If there is anyone else
除了你和孟
knows the address of Wangyun Road
除了你和黎秋实
except you, Li Qiushi
还有骆警官一家人
and the family of Luo?
有谁知道望云路的地址
Wait and see.
等一下吧
We'll get the answer soon.
很快就会知道答案了
Brother, Dad wants you to...
哥 爸让你
Something wrong?
你怎么了
I'm fine.
没事儿 没事儿
What was it?
怎么了
Dad wants you to
爸让你
buy more medicine for sister.
再给姐姐抓两服药
I'll go now.
我我我 我现在去
I've paid my debt.
钱不是都给你们了吗
What do you want more?
你们还想干啥呀
I heard from the boss that
听老板说
you would get 30 silver dollars reward
等赏金一到
after he got the bounty.
再给你三十块
Is it true?
有这事儿吗
I did it
我去麻将馆
just for paying back the money.
就是为了凑够你们的钱
I won't ask more than I should get.
多的钱我不能要
I won't take that money.
那个钱我不能拿
Tianxiang,
天祥啊
we heard your sister officer
听说你警察妹妹
was beaten badly.
被人打了呀
Well, we three should
那以后咱哥仨
take care of our sister then.
得好好照顾妹妹了
No.
大哥 不是
My sister has nothing to do with this.
你别把我妹妹牵扯进来
I beg you.
我求你们了
Do what I told you to do.
没靠山了你就老实点儿
Take it when I ask you to take.
我让你拿你就拿
You follow my order.
我让你怎么着就怎么着
Is he your helper?
还有帮手
Captain Chen.
陈队长
I thought you forgot me.
还知道我叫陈队长
No, I didn't.
知道
Got more guts lately?
长本事了
No.
没 没有
We're brothers.
这都 都自己家兄弟
Yes, we're friends.
对 自己家兄弟
Well, I'll leave you in peace.
那个没 没什么事儿
We'll go now.
那咱先走了
Bye, Tianxiang.
走了 天祥
Wait.
等等
Apologize.
道歉
Turn round.
向后转
Sorry.
对不起
Which direction did you turn?
你往哪儿转呢
Rember this
记住了
even if Officer Luo was not a police officer anymore,
就算骆警官不当警察
you will never bully her.
也由不得你们欺负
Got it?
记住了吗
Yes, sir.
记住了 明白
Get lost.
走
Thank you, Captain.
谢谢陈队长
Thank you, Officer Xiang.
谢谢向警官
That day
那天
when you and Qiushi visited us,
你和秋实来家里吃饭
my father bought a cake for Qiushi.
爸给秋实买了个蛋糕
But he forgot to give it to her.
走的时候忘拿了
So he ordered me go to ask the
就让我去
the driver of rickshaw, Li
拉车的李师傅家
for your address.
问了你们的地址
And whom did you tell?
然后你告诉谁了
The owner of the mahjong parlor
我工作的
where I was working.
那家麻将馆老板
This.
这
This photo is from him.
这照片就是他给我的
He said that was a business from the black market.
说是从黑市上接的生意
Someone was looking for the girl
有人要找
in the picture.
照片上的小姑娘
He asked the people in mahjong parlor
就让麻将馆的人
to search for the girl.
都跟着一起找
It's said that the girl was worth a high bounty.
还说赏金特别高
The moment I saw the picture,
其实我拿到照片的时候
I knew who she was.
我就认出她来了
But I hadn't told the owner.
但我一直没告诉老板
However, the hatchet men threatened me
是因为刚才那几个人说
if I didn't give back the money,
说 说再不给钱
they'd burn down my father's photo shop.
就要烧了爸爸的照相馆
I was really scared.
我 我实在是害怕了我
I'm sorry for Minmin and Qiushi.
是我对不起珉敏和秋实
I have a sister, too.
我也是有妹妹的人
I don't know why they
我不知道那帮人
are after her.
为什么要找她
But she must be in trouble.
但肯定是有麻烦了
I don't mean to do that.
我不想害了小姑娘
But I have no options.
但我真是没办法了
This is the end of it.
这件事情到此为止
Never let Luo Minmin know it.
永远不要让骆珉敏知道
Sorry.
对不起
Where will you move to?
那你打算搬去哪儿
I have no idea.
还没想过
To investigate the mahjong parlor first.
先去查麻将馆
Then put on the uniform.
那还是把警服穿上吧
I've been suspended.
我停职了
Only you are the police now.
现在只有你是警察
Captain Chen welcome you.
陈队长来了
Where is your boss?
老板呢
He's inside.
搁屋呢
I guess you remember this picture.
这张照片你应该有印象
Tell me
我想知道
who gave it to you?
是谁给你的
Dealings
这黑市的买卖呢
in black market
讲究的就是一个
should be traceless.
不明不白
If I break the rule
我今天要是在二位这儿
before you today,
破了规矩
I'll lose much in the future.
今后这生意就没法做了
No one knows what will happen
今后的事情
in the future.
谁也不敢保证
But now
但眼下
you got a chance to earn double
你可以一个消息
out of one dealing
做两笔买卖
without losing any.
不亏本
This is Yao Ji.
这是幺鸡
Er...
这
Captain Chen,
陈队长
the friend of yours
您这位朋友
is so honest
怕真是个空子
and knows nothing about the rules.
不懂规矩啊
Tell us how much do you want directly.
你就直接说多少钱
This mahjong
这一索嘛
represents 100 Yuan.
自然指的是一百块
Well,
当然
if you can't afford it.
您要是给不起这钱
Deal.
成交
Well.
这
We can afford it.
我们给你一百
Dare you take it?
你敢拿吗
What does Captain Chen mean?
那陈队长的意思是
I know the rules.
规矩我懂
That's yours.
就这么多
I will never
我这个人呢
behave badly when it comes to
是肯定不会
cooperating with the police.
跟警察过不去的是吧
However,
不过陈队长
Captain Chen,
您可得确保
you must make sure that
黑市那边
the one in black market won't trouble me.
查不到我的头上
Tell me who gave it to you.
说 谁给的
Alright.
行
Today, I will give Captain Chen
今天
this courtesy.
我就卖陈队长这个面子
This picture
这张照片啊
is given by
是
Mr. Fan, the owner of the Dongguang pawnshop.
东光当铺的范老板给的
I must remind you two
好心提醒二位一句啊
don't go into dead end.
当心有去无回
Before visiting officer Luo,
去骆警官家之前
I'll draw cash and return your money.
我先去趟银行把钱还你
Ronghua is right.
老左说得没错
Money helps a lot.
有时候钱啊确实管用
Don't return it.
不用还了
How much do you own?
你有几个钱
Money isn't a problem for me.
我又不缺钱
Officer,
警官
May I ask if you are pawning things
敢问您今天是当东西
or redeeming things today?
还是赎东西啊
I'm here to find Mr. Fan.
我找范老板
May I have your name?
您是
He didn't know me.
他不认识我
If you have any questions,
那您有什么事儿
I might help, too.
跟小的说也行
I want to know
我想知道
who is after the girl
是谁在找
in this picture?
照片上这个女孩儿
Officer,
警官
you must be kidding.
您真会说笑
This is a pawn shop.
我们这是当铺
I don't understand
小的听不明白
what you're saying.
您在说什么
You understand.
你明白
Please wait a minute.
那你等会儿
Looking for help?
叫人去啊
It's the call of nature.
尿急 尿急
Hold it.
憋着